*music*
Well, good morning, Canvas Community Church, family, friends.
So good to see you all for this first week of Advent.
I decided to rock the Bluey shirt.
Hopefully many of you got the announcement
that some of my message is gonna be using
a Bluey episode as an illustration.
We'll get into that in just a little bit.
Last week, Kent started our Advent series
on the names of God given to us in the Bible.
And when God reveals to us different names and titles,
it helps us better understand who he is
and how he relates to us.
Because the Bible is all about us being invited
into a relationship with God, amen?
So for the rest of our Advent,
we are going to look at a list of titles or names
that the prophet Isaiah gives God about Jesus
before he comes.
This was to prepare them so that they would recognize
when he arrived.
So Marissa and I do this on a regular basis
before we take Rory to the doctor, right?
When we know that we're about to take Rory to the doctor,
we use this title of doctor to prepare him.
We have a good doctor, right?
Rory, tomorrow we are going to see Dr. Grant.
Therefore, you know how to mentally prepare.
And he'll start pointing to his ear like,
yep, he's gonna stick that thing in my ear.
I know that's what's gonna happen.
Because the title helps prepare him for what's to come.
And so in this list of titles that Isaiah gives us,
it is preparing us for what the Messiah is going to be
when he comes the first time,
what he's inviting us to participate in
as we await for him to come the second time.
My hope is by the end of this short message,
I promise it will be short.
I'm probably gonna stick to my notes far more
than I normally do because if I don't,
it will not be a short message.
So by the end of this message,
I hope that we can begin to better understand
what it means for Jesus to be our wonderful counselor.
This is the first title we're gonna look at.
Can you look at your neighbor and say wonderful?
Can you look at your other neighbor and say counselor?
Hopefully by the end of this message,
we'll understand what it means for Jesus
to be our wonderful counselor
and why that should give us hope.
This confident expectation that what Jesus says is true
and we can hold tight to it.
Let's pray.
Father in heaven, we love you
and we thank you for this wonderful family of God
that you have brought together under this one roof with floors.
We are so grateful to be here
and we just look forward to what you are going to do
and what you have already done
and what you're going to continue to do
through not just this service,
but through the family that we are becoming.
Because the church is so much more
than what we do on Sunday mornings,
it's who we are throughout the week together
in one another's lives.
And so God, form in us your image for your glory.
It's in Jesus' name I pray, amen.
All right, I tried to get the word out.
So hopefully as many of you as possible
were able to watch the episode of Bluey called The Creek.
Raise your hand if you were able to see it.
All right, awesome.
Many of you are there.
So for those of you that missed it,
I'm gonna try and do a quick recap of the episode.
Bluey and her friends are playing on the playground,
but they get bored.
Imagine that.
Bluey wants her dad to play with her,
but he's too big for the playground toys.
Dad, she wants dad to play.
Dad can't play on the playground
because I mean, look at him.
He's a bit chunky.
He needs to go on a Christmas diet.
It's fine.
So he invites her, convinces her
that if she wants him to play with her,
they can walk down to the creek.
She's a bit nervous, a bit anxious about the trip,
but eventually she gives in to her dad's advice.
It doesn't take long before she's changed her mind.
Spider webs, leeches, and sliding down hills.
The path is more difficult
than she ever could have anticipated.
The idea of the creek seemed more beautiful
than the creek itself.
And if you have, hopefully you have a coloring sheet.
We're gonna get to some notes on the back,
just so you know.
We're gonna follow along there.
So she's pretty nervous.
Obviously, spider webs and leeches
might make the most brave of us nervous,
but her dad picks her up.
He encourages her to keep going
and he goes before her.
He knows the trip is doable
and the reward is great
because as a kid, he has done this trip many times.
Finally, the hard work pays off
as they arrive at the creek.
Bluey gasps, the creek is beautiful.
And dad asks, do you want to go back to the playground?
And Bluey explains, no, I like it here.
This episode, in my view,
gives us a clear and beautiful picture
for how Jesus operates
as the wonderful counselor in our lives.
Jesus functions much like Bluey's father,
inviting us into a more beautiful image
of what creation really is,
of what being a human is really like
than we could ever imagine on our own.
But it takes us following his counsel.
As the wonderful counselor,
it takes us having the faith
to walk the difficult path
that the father has laid out before us.
And so in Isaiah chapter nine,
we get this list of titles
and it says,
for a child is born to us.
A son is given,
the government shall rest on his shoulders
and he will be called Wonderful Counselor,
Mighty God, Everlasting Father,
Prince of Peace.
The government and its peace will never end.
He will rule with fairness and justice
from the throne of his ancestor David
for all eternity.
The passionate commitment
of the Lord of Heaven's armies
will make this happen.
So as we look at our notes
and we see this title
of Wonderful Counselor,
the Hebrew word for wonderful
literally is too good to describe, right?
It's a placeholder word.
It's a word saying,
we don't have a word
to be as good as the word we need,
so wonderful is the word we're gonna use.
Wonderful means too good
to put into words.
This is the adjective
that describes the type of counselor
that God is.
And a counselor,
what does a counselor do?
A counselor gives us direction
that leads to joy.
So if you have your notes,
you can follow along with me.
If you are an older kid
and your younger sibling
maybe struggles with writing,
would love for you to help them
take notes,
be a good example to them.
Wonderful, too good
to put into words counselor.
It gives us direction
that leads to joy.
Now, I want us to notice
in this passage
that when God sends Jesus
to be our wonderful counselor,
he does so by sending a child.
Not a big, mighty warrior,
but a small and humble child.
And so if you're in here
and you're a child,
I want you to hear
that God can and will use you
for his purposes now.
You do not need to wait
until you get bigger
to know God
and work alongside him.
He is inviting you to do so now.
And actually,
there's stories in the gospel
where it seems like
he wants all of the adults
to come to him
like you all come to him.
And so please know
that you are invited
to participate
in a relationship
with the creator
of the universe.
He is your wonderful counselor.
He wants to give you advice
that leads to joy.
And you can begin
walking that path now.
You can avoid lots of problems
and difficulties
that many of us
have stepped into
because we weren't following Jesus
as our wonderful counselor.
Adults, our children,
and this,
I'm talking to those of you
that even if you don't have children,
all of the children
that are a part of our church
are not just the church of tomorrow.
They are the church of today
and they need all of us,
parents and not parents,
to encourage and equip them
in their relationship with him.
Jesus comes as a child
to be the savior of the world.
And as the savior of the world,
he is our wonderful counselor
that gives us direction
that leads to joy.
So, first point in the notes,
I think is this,
that Jesus tells us
the direction we should go.
Jesus, as our wonderful counselor,
announces to us
the direction that we should go.
As our wonderful counselor,
he declares this is the way to go.
He declares I am the way,
the truth, and the life.
Anyone who would come to the Father
must come by me,
by following me,
by taking my advice.
And if you've ever had the experience
of going to a counselor,
some of you maybe have had good counselors,
some of you have had bad counselors,
but the best counselors give good direction.
They look at the circumstances of your life,
the situations that you have experienced,
the things,
the behaviors that you have developed
through those experiences,
and they tell you
where you're believing things
that aren't true.
And they invite you
into a different direction
that will ultimately lead to more joy.
I've had a good counselor in my life,
and this is what he does for me.
He asks me good questions.
He examines my circumstances
and my behaviors,
and he invites me to go
in a different direction
that leads to joy.
Good counselors,
the best counselors,
they study how the brain works,
how the body interacts with the world,
and they can see when something is wrong
and help us move in the right direction.
But Jesus isn't just a good counselor.
He's a wonderful one.
Too good for words.
He doesn't have to study our body
and our brains because he created them.
He made you unique in your mother's womb,
and he knows the direction you need to go
in order to experience joy.
Jesus, the wonderful counselor,
gives good advice that leads to joy.
In one of his most well-known sermons
in Matthew chapter five through seven
called the Sermon on the Mount,
he spends time doing this.
He spends time telling people
the direction that they should go.
He starts with phrases like,
you have heard it said,
or everyone around you believes this thing,
but I say to you.
So he starts with something we all believe,
and as a wonderful counselor,
he says,
let me give you some better advice
that ultimately leads to the life
that I'm inviting you to.
You have heard it said,
an eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth,
but I say to you,
if someone slaps you on the cheek,
you should turn to them the other cheek.
This is Jesus functioning
as our wonderful counselor,
telling us the way that we should go,
and the way that we should go is difficult, right?
It's much easier when someone punches you
to punch them back.
Isn't that the thing that we all want to do
when we get hit,
or when we get slapped,
or when we get made fun of,
or when we get pushed down,
the thing that we want to do is push back.
We wanna get up,
and we wanna fight harder.
We wanna take the pain that they've caused us
and cause them more pain,
but Jesus says,
if you wanna experience true life,
the life that I've created you for,
the way that you experience that
is not by doing what everyone else says.
You have heard it said.
Someone hits you,
you hit back,
but I say to you,
you turn the other cheek.
He goes on,
you have heard it said,
love your neighbor and hate your enemy.
This is somewhat wise advice, right?
Love the people that are around you
that can benefit you,
and anybody that comes after you
or attacks you,
attack them back.
But I say to you,
love your enemies
and pray for those who persecute you.
Jesus takes worldly wisdom,
advice.
This is playground living, right?
This is how we live and interact with people
apart from a relationship with God.
Bluey on the playground
without her father's input.
It's fine for a while.
It might work,
but eventually it will,
the joy will run out.
And the only place
where we can ultimately find full joy
is to run to the father
for the relationship
that we were created to.
And when we look to him,
he says,
you have heard it said,
hate your enemy,
but I say,
love your enemy
and pray for those
who persecute you.
Just,
I just want you for just a second
to imagine the type of world
that would be created
if God's people,
if all of God's people
actually lived the words of Jesus.
If we actually viewed him
as the wonderful counselor,
if we actually viewed his voice,
his advice as advice
that leads us to deeper joy.
Imagine the type of world
that we would create
when every time somebody hits us,
we pray
and we ask God's blessing
on those people.
Sounds very difficult, Eliza.
You are so right.
And that is why
following Jesus is hard,
but ultimately,
it is the way
that we should go.
The playground's easy.
The creek is beautiful.
It's what we've been invited to.
Because Jesus
is the wonderful counselor, Eliza,
he doesn't just tell us
what we should do,
but he gives us an example.
He gives us the direction.
Second point in our notes
is that Jesus leads the way.
The direction that Jesus invites us to
is hard to hear.
He knows that this is a scary invitation.
He doesn't just tell us
what to do from afar,
but he gets down dirty with us.
That's what Advent is all about.
That Jesus was born a little baby.
That he experienced enemies
hitting him and slapping him
and making fun of him.
That he experienced all the pain
and difficulty
that you and I will face.
And in experiencing that,
he doesn't just say,
love your enemies,
but he actually does it before us.
He goes before us.
He shows us an example.
He accomplishes the thing
that we could never accomplish
because it is too hard for us to do.
And he invites us
to imperfectly follow behind his example.
To receive the grace and forgiveness
that he gives us.
Jesus doesn't just tell us
not to repay evil with evil.
He shows us.
He doesn't just tell us
to love our enemies.
He shows us.
Jesus went to the cross
to show us the ultimate example.
He loved us
even when we were his enemies.
And even on the cross,
as his enemies were doing
the worst possible thing
that anyone could do to anyone,
something that none of us
have experienced,
he looked up to the heavens
and he prayed to the Father,
Father, forgive them
for they do not know
what they are doing.
Jesus is our wonderful counselor
who both tells us
the direction that leads to life
and shows us the way.
And even though
it's the most complicated,
difficult invitation
that you could ever imagine,
he gave us this anchoring point,
this lighthouse
in the midst of the storm.
And that lighthouse
is the resurrection.
The resurrection proves
that the way of Jesus
is the way that leads to victory
and all other ways will fail.
Fighting back against your enemy,
doing what the world does,
it might work for a while,
it might be easier in the moment,
but it will fail.
The resurrection proves
the only time
that anyone's death
wasn't eternal
was when they lived
this perfect way of being.
And Jesus says,
if you want to have victory,
if you want to have eternal life,
if you want to experience
the beauty of the kingdom of God
before I return
and all of the plowshares
will be beat into,
or all of the swords
will be beat into plowshares,
if you want to begin
to experience the life
of the kingdom of God now,
you follow me.
We often get tricked
into believing
that we can have true life
by following our own way
and it will work for a while,
but eventually it will stop
because ultimately
we were made
for a relationship with God.
It's just like Bluey
on the playground,
life without her dad.
It's good for a while,
but ultimately it runs out
and she runs to the father
and says,
I want to play with you,
but if you want to play with him,
you've got to go where he goes
and he can't be where we are.
He is in the kingdom of God
and that is what we are invited
to participate in.
The path is difficult
and we will often be tempted
to turn around.
There are leeches
and spider webs
and slippery slopes
on the way of Jesus.
The road is narrow
that leads to life.
It is difficult.
No one is going to tell you
differently from this pulpit
and if they do,
thank you.
Don't trust them.
There we go.
Don't trust me.
The path is difficult.
We will often be tempted
to turn around,
but true life is found
in following Jesus
no matter how hard
the path gets.
So,
have you made this decision
to follow Jesus
as your wonderful counselor
who both tells us
the way that leads us to joy
and shows us
the way that we should live?
Are we focused on following him
and embodying his way
of being in the world?
Or are we getting distracted
by the difficulty
of the road?
The invitation this morning
as we remember
Christ's first coming
and anticipate
his second coming
is to view his advice
and his example
as the path
to follow
as a wonderful counselor.
Hebrews chapter 12
verses 1 and 2
says it this way.
Let us strip off
every weight
that slows us down,
especially the sin
that so easily
trips us up
and let us run
with endurance
the race
that God has set
before us.
This is a relationship
with Jesus.
This is living
in the kingdom of God.
It is a race,
a long race.
We need to pace ourselves
and we need to keep
our eyes on Jesus,
the champion
who goes before us
and initiates
and perfects
our faith.
Jesus is
the wonderful counselor.
He tells us
the direction
that we should go
and he leads
the way.
This is what it looks
like for us
to view Jesus
as the wonderful counselor.
And if we do,
what we will begin
to experience
as the kingdom
of God begins
to become more clear
and embodied
in our family
is we will see
that the kingdom
of God
is beautiful.
It's difficult,
it's complicated,
and before Christ
returns,
it will be messy,
but we will see it
even if through
a dimly lit mirror.
The kingdom
of God
is beautiful.
And I want to,
as we start
to wrap up,
I want to make
this connection
between what Jesus
is as the wonderful
counselor
and this first week
that we are celebrating
in the Advent,
this first week
of hope.
Because in the Bible,
hope is not wishful
thinking,
but it is a confident
expectation.
We can have confidence
that Jesus will do
what he says
he will do
because he has
accomplished
all of the prophecies
that were taught
about him.
Jesus has brought
hope to a world
without hope.
He promised us
eternal life,
joy,
and peace.
If we follow him,
we can be confident
we will get
where we are going
even when the road
gets hard
because Jesus
is leading the way.
This is what it looks
like for us
to have hope
in the midst
of difficult circumstances
as we look
to Jesus,
our wonderful counselor,
who both explains
to us the way
that we should go
to experience joy
and leads the way,
sets an example
for us.
And like Eliza
pointed out for all
of us,
it is not easy.
It is hard.
But it is beautiful.
This is my hope
for my son.
It's my hope
for all of you
is that you would
catch a vision
for the kingdom
of God
that is so much
better than the
kingdom of this world.
that as you watch
your friends
and your families
who don't know Jesus
slapping each other
back and forth,
escalating the fighting,
escalating the separation,
escalating the division
that we as people
of the kingdom
would step in
with grace and peace
and that we would love
and pray for our enemies.
That we would
become the thing
that we are expecting
Jesus to bring back
as we wait for him.
that he would be
our wonderful counselor.
This,
I hope
for our church,
for the church
in our cities
and for the church
across the world
that we would stop,
that we would lay down
our weapons
and that we would
pick up our pruning shears.
We are waiting
for that to happen fully
and that's why
it gets complicated
but we do it
with confidence
because Jesus
went before us
and he proved
that victory is there
through the resurrection.
And so even
if we experience
death by following
this way,
it is death
that will ultimately
lead to resurrection.
Merry Christmas,
children.
I'm gonna pray
while I'm praying
if the worship team
and those of you
that are gonna be baptized
wanna come forward.
Baptism people
can gather over here.
Worship team's gonna
lead us in
some more,
another song.
Let's pray.
Father in heaven,
we are so grateful
that Jesus
is our wonderful counselor.
That this child
that was born to us,
that was promised
hundreds of years
before his birth,
that he did indeed come.
That he did fulfill
all of the promises
and prophecies
that you made about him.
that he is indeed
the wonderful counselor
who tells us
the way that leads
to ultimate joy
and resurrection
and hope.
But he doesn't just tell us,
he goes before us,
he sets an example
before us,
he succeeds
where we will fail.
And we can be confident
that we will reach
our ultimate destination,
not because we can do it
on our own,
but because we follow
behind him.
the one who has already
walked the narrow road
that leads
to life.
Father,
may we,
our families
and our children
be people
of the kingdom
that learn
to walk
and step
with you,
keeping our eyes
on you,
the author
and perfecter
of our faith,
who for the joy
set before him
endured the cross,
endured the enemy,
endured the pain.
And may we experience
the resurrection life
that you offer us.
It's in Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.